DAVID KAVANAGH

Personal Information

Email: davykavanagh@gmail.com Phone Number: +44 7414023126

Github: https://github.com/DavyK Website: https://davy.tech/

I am a software engineer with a passion for building products that people find easy and fun to use. Most of my experience is in web design/development. I am comfortable at all levels of the stack, from requirements gathering and schema design all the way through to frontend development. In my spare time, I write some fiction, and do some amateur game development.

Work Experience

Nov 2018 – Present: Product Engineer, Intercom, London

Role: Designing and building product features across the backend and frontend. Responsibilities included designing and implementing technical solutions to deliver impactful features, communicating with customers to identify problems to be solved, and managing the roll out of large features for thousands of customers. **Technologies used:** Ruby (rails), Javascript (Vanilla, Ember JS, React), databases (Mysql, Mongo, Aws Redshift, Elasticsearch, Redis). **Other tools:** Git, Github, Python (for data analysis), Docker, docker-compose, data-dog, honeycomb.

Apr 2016 – Nov 2018: Software Developer, Oxford Nanopore Technologies, Oxford, UK

Role: Full stack development of several different data tracking and reporting micro services. Responsible for deploying and maintaining several different APIs and frontend applications to capture and report on diverse data sources. Micro services are maintained and deployed using a continuous integration strategy. **Technologies used:** Python (django, flask), Javascript (Node, React, Redux), Uwsgi, Nginx, databases (MySQL, Postgresql, MongoDB, Redis, Elasticsearch), **Other tools:** Celery, Docker, Docker-compose, Docker-swarm, Git, GitLab CI, Kibana, Grafana, Prometheus.

September 2014 – April 2016: Postdoctoral Fellow Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, NY, USA

Role: Genetic and genomics research into adult psychiatric disorders. Designed, implemented, tested and deployed a suite of data processing, analysis and visualisation tools for various data types, in a high throughput distributed environment. **Technologies used:** R, python (django, numpy, scipy, pandas), javascript (jquery, jquery-ui), databases (postgres, MongoDB), Git.

June 2012 – August 2014: Postdoctoral Research Associate Cardiff University Cardiff, Wales, UK

Role: As above.

Education

2015 – 2106: Full stack Web Developer Nanodegree https://www.udacity.com

2009 - 2012: PhD in Genetics and Bioinformatics Queens University Belfast, Co. Antrim,

Northern Ireland

2008 - 2009: MSc. Molecular Medicine Queens University Belfast, Co. Antrim, Northern Ireland

2002 – 2006: BSc. Single Honors NUI Maynooth, Co. Kildare, Ireland

References:

References are available on request.